[生物的叫声]
[creature squawking]
[动物的叫声]
[creatures squawking]
[生物继续尖叫]
[creatures continue squawking]
[嘟嘟嘟嘟的歌]
[doo-wop song playing]
在山上
♪ Over the mountain ♪
穿过大海
♪ Across the sea ♪
有个女孩在等我
♪ There's a girl She's waiting for me ♪
[打哈欠]
[yawning]
[呻吟声]
[moans]
“过河”
♪ Cross over the river ♪
在每一片云彩之外
♪ Beyond every cloud ♪
“她已经过去了”
♪ She's passed the wind ♪
[隆隆声]
[rumbling]
“吹得很响”
♪ That's blowing loud ♪
[呻吟声]
[moans]
在山上
♪ Over the mountain ♪
一个女孩在等我
♪ A girl waits for me ♪
告诉所有的沙子
♪ Tell all the sands ♪
[嗅探]
[sniffing]
“还有每一片草”
♪ And every blade of grass ♪
嗯。
Mm.
“请告诉风让我的爱过去”
♪ Please tell the wind to let my love pass ♪
[低声咆哮]
[growling softly]
在山上
♪ Over the mountain ♪
一个女孩在等我
♪ A girl waits for me ♪
[设备呼啸声]
[device whirring]
[沉重的脚步声]
[heavy footsteps thudding]
[隐约的脚步声]
[faint, muffled footsteps]
[低沉的呼噜声]
[muffled grunting]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[大声吼叫]
[roaring loudly]
[远处爆炸]
[distant explosion]
[软爆炸]
[soft explosion]
[警报声]
[alarm blares]
[扬声器上的自动语音]警报，生物圆顶破裂。
[automated voice on speaker] Alert, biodome breach.
警报，生物圆顶破裂。
Alert, biodome breach.
安德鲁斯医生，你看到了吗？
Dr. Andrews, did you see that?
栖息地撑不了多久了。
The habitat's not gonna hold much longer.
我们需要开始考虑非现场解决方案。
We need to start thinking about off-site solutions.
岛是唯一让他与世隔绝的地方。
The island is the one thing that's kept him isolated.
如果他走了，哥斯拉会来找他的。
If he leaves, Godzilla will come for him.
不可能有两个阿尔法泰坦。
There can't be two alpha Titans.
古代竞争的整个理论
The whole theory of an ancient rivalry
源于Iwi神话。
stems from Iwi mythology.
他长得太大了。
He's gotten too big over time.
这种环境维持不了多久。
This environment won't sustain much longer.
太不稳定了。
It's too unstable.
嘿。
Hey.
[手语]
[in sign language]
[叹息声]
[sighs]
离开现场会被判死刑。
Off-site would be a death sentence.
你不认为国王能照顾好自己吗？
You don't think the King could take care of himself?
一定有别的办法。
There has to be another way.
找到这些生物的起源
[man 1]  Finding the origin of these creatures
对人类的生存至关重要。
is essential to mankind's survival.
地球内部
[man 2]  The interior of the Earth
由巨大的舱室和气穴组成，
is made up of vast cabins and air pockets,
自然的道路连接在一起。
joined by natural avenues.
海军上将开始了他的探险，
[man 3]  The admiral begins his expedition,
寻找一个隐秘世界的入口。
searching for an entrance to a hidden world.
[男4]目的是发现
[man 4]  The purpose is the discovery
以及向世界的释放
and the release to the world
南极洲未知的宝藏
of the unknown treasures of Antarctica
为了全人类的利益。
in the interests of all mankind.
迷路党的成员再也没有露面。
[man 5]  Members of the lost party were never seen again.
仍然没有关于可能发生了什么的消息。
Still no word on what may have happened.
外面有一个生态系统，
[man 6]  There's an ecosystem out there,
我们无法想象的那种。
the likes of which we can't imagine.
找到它的地方就是这个岛。
And the place to find it is this island.
[咆哮声]
[growling]
[男]你好，忠实的听众。
[man]  Hello, loyal listeners.
欢迎来到TTP，泰坦真相播客。
Welcome to  TTP, Titan Truth Podcast.
第245集。
Episode number 245.
今天就是今天。
Today is the day.
可能是我录制的最后一个播客。
Maybe the last podcast I ever record.
听着，我知道我上周说过
And look, I know I said that last week
可能是前一周或者其他几次。
and maybe the week before and a few other times.
但是，听着，这就是重点。
But, look, this is the point.
在Apex控制论公司深造了五年之后，
After five years of deep cover at Apex Cybernetics,
我终于要开枪了。
I'm finally taking my shot.
这里发生了不好的事情。
Something bad is going on here.
我不知道是什么，
I don't know what it is,
但我要进去下载确凿的证据
but I'm about to walk in and download hard evidence
揭露一个庞大的公司阴谋。
and expose a vast corporate conspiracy.
是的，你可以叫我告密者，
Yeah, you can call me a whistleblower,
但我不只是吹口哨。
but I ain't just whistling.
我的意思是，这不仅仅是一个漏洞。这是一场洪水。
I mean, this is more than a leak. It's a flood.
相信我，这场洪水
And believe me, this flood
会洗去Apex所有的谎言。
is gonna wash away all of Apex's lies.
你可以相信。
You can believe that.
[自动语音扬声器]欢迎来到Apex控制论。
[automated voice on speaker] Welcome to Apex Cybernetics.
未经授权的人员不得超过此点。
No unauthorized persons allowed beyond this point.
[电视上的人]当我们开始研究控制论的时候，
[man on TV]  When we started Apex Cybernetics,
我们梦想着新的方法
we dreamt of new ways
超越人类潜能的极限。
to push past the limits of human potential.
机器人技术，人类思维，人工智能。
Robotics, the human mind, artificial intelligence.
谁知道我们下一步会梦想什么样的未来？
Who knows what brave new future we'll dream of next?
我是沃尔特·西蒙斯，
I'm Walter Simmons,
我很荣幸能领导Apex
and it is my privilege to lead Apex
进入人类大胆的新时代。
into humanity's bold new era.
我们哪儿也不去。
We're not going anywhere.
你也是。
And neither are you.
你在这儿，宝贝。
[man] There you are, baby.
[收音机里模糊的谈话声]
[indistinct chatter on radio]
不，别吃那个！
No, don't eat that!
这是非常不健康的。
It's incredibly unhealthy.
全是转基因生物。
It's just all the GMOs.
长第二个头可能有用。
Growing a second head could be useful.
你得让我知道。
You have to let me know.
因为我，我自己？
Because me, myself?
我几乎不能处理我得到的那个。[咯咯笑]
I can barely handle the one I got. [chuckles]
伯尼，你不应该在这里。
Bernie, you're not supposed to be in here.
你有没有想过我们到底在干什么？
You ever wonder what we're really doing here?
我是说，真的在这里干什么。
I mean, really doing here.
你为什么在这里？
Why are you here?
这不是工程。
This isn't Engineering.
因为，你知道，我不得不等待
Because, you know, I had to wait
因为他们正在渲染这些新的规格，
because they're rendering these new specs,
它将接管，呃。。。
which is gonna take over, uh...
这是计算器模式。
That's calculator mode.
…一个多小时，甚至更多。
...over one hour, maybe even more.
所以我的工头让我出去走走
So my foreman told me to just take a walk
-结交一些新朋友。-哦。
-and make some new friends. -Oh.
哦！既然我们是新朋友，
Oh! Now that we're new friends,
我可以和你分享一些东西，对吗？
I can share something with you, right?
我知道它在这里的某个地方。
I know it's in here somewhere.
这是我用自己的花园做的洗手液。
This is hand sanitizer that I made from my own garden.
真是太神奇了。
It's really amazing.
不知道我用不用。
Don't know if I used that or not.
[惊呼声]
[exclaims]
对。这个。看看这个。
Yes. This. Check this out.
那就是无线网状网络
That right there is radio mesh networking
使用语音记录子处理器。
with a voice-record subprocessor.
-从哪里猜。来吧。-我不在乎。
-Guess from where. Come on. -I don't care.
烤面包机！[咯咯笑]
A toaster! [chuckles]
是烤面包机里的。看看这个东西。
It's from a toaster. Look at this thing.
我得去洗手间。
I have to go to the bathroom.
是一个还是两个？
Is it one or two?
因为如果是两个，很可能是这些苹果。
'Cause if it's two, it's probably from these apples.
嘿，你想用我做的洗手液吗？
Hey, you wanna use the hand sanitizer that I made?
我很好。
I'm good.
好吧，我就呆在这里。
Okay, I'll just stay here.
[轻轻地]好的。是 啊。
[softly] Okay. Yeah.
啊，让我看看。
Ah, let's see.
喔。
Whoo.
屏幕。
Screen.
他们向香港运送什么？
What are they shipping to Hong Kong?
第33级是什么？
What's Sublevel 33?
什么。。。？
What the...?
-[警报声]-[喘息声]
-[alarm blares] -[gasps]
撤离，泰坦警报。
[automated voice on pa] Evacuation, Titan alert.
这不是演习。
[man on PA] This is not a drill.
所有Apex员工，请继续。。。
All Apex employees, please proceed...
那是我的提示。那是我的提示。
That is my cue. That's my cue.
这不是演习。
[man on PA] This is not a drill.
[含糊不清的喊叫]
[indistinct shouting]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
排成一排去辐射掩体。
Proceed to the fallout shelter in a single-file line.
走吧！
Let's go!
他们用氰化物胶囊
[man] They used cyanide capsules
而不是用放射性尘埃掩体来保守秘密，
instead of fallout shelters to keep the secrets in,
但是，你知道，那不是这里也不是那里，
but, you know, that's neither here nor there,
所以别听我说。
so don't listen to me.
二级人员，这边！快走，快走！
[guard] Level two personnel, this way! Let's go, let's go!
是的，那边。
Yeah, that way.
是时候！
It's time!
我们得走了！
We need to go now!
[含糊不清的喊叫]
[indistinct shouting]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
[自动语音]撤离。
[automated voice]  Evacuate.
[喘气]一次一级，好的。
[panting] One level at a time, okay.
-不。-嘿，你！
-No. -Hey, you!
-你的通行证呢？-你知道吗？
-Where's your clearance tag? -You know what?
你说的事实
The fact that you're talking about
在危机时刻的清关标签
clearance tags right now in a time of crisis
非常不专业。
is incredibly unprofessional.
我们应该谈谈撤离。
We should be talking about evacuation.
-[公鸡的枪]-哟！可以！
-[cocks gun] -Yo! Okay!
-[隆隆声]-[伯尼尖叫]
-[rumbling] -[Bernie yelps]
-[高声尖叫]-[尖叫声]
-[high-pitched screech] -[screams]
[伯尼咳嗽]
[Bernie coughing]
哦，天哪。
[grunts] Oh, my God.
[机械的叮当声]
[mechanical warbling and clanking]
哦，不。那到底是什么？
Oh, no. What the hell is that?
[机械叮当声]
[mechanical clanking]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
[咆哮声]
[roaring]
[新闻主题音乐播放]
[news theme music plays]
这是CNN的新闻。
[announcer] This is CNN breaking news.
[主播]美国海军第四舰队
[anchor]  The United States Navy's Fourth Fleet
部署在东南沿海
is deployed off the southeastern seaboard
在昨晚哥斯拉突然袭击之后。
of the U.S. after last night's sudden Godzilla attack.
一段相对平静的时期被打破了
A time of relative peace shattered
当巨大的泰坦，
when the massive Titan,
曾经被认为是人类的英雄，
once thought to be a hero to humanity,
在佛罗里达州的彭萨科拉登陆。
made landfall in Pensacola, Florida.
虽然损失基本得到控制
While the damage was largely contained
致美国Apex控制论总部，
to the U.S. headquarters of Apex Cybernetics,
世界各国政府都没有冒险
governments around the world aren't taking any chances
在第一次被证实的土卫六目击之后
after the first substantiated Titan sighting
三年多了。
in over three years.
首席执行官沃尔特·西蒙斯有话要说。
CEO Walter Simmons had this to say.
这是为了共同努力确保一个更安全的世界。
It's about working together to ensure a safer world.
哥斯拉是对人类的威胁，
Godzilla's a threat to humanity,
Apex有个解决方案，
and Apex has a plan to deal with it,
-一劳永逸。-[上课铃响]
-once and for all. -[school bell rings]
学生和教员，
[woman on PA] Students and faculty,
将举行强制集会
a mandatory assembly will be held
今天下午两点。
at 2:00 p.m. this afternoon.
指导顾问也将举行
Guidance counselors will also be holding
本周额外的办公时间
additional office hours all this week
个人和小组会议。
for individual and group sessions.
欢迎回来，忠实的听众，
[Bernie on speaker] Welcome back, loyal listeners,
泰坦真相播客，第246集。
to  Titan Truth Podcast, episode 246.
哦，天哪。我当时在场。
Oh, my God. I was there.
哥斯拉的顶点攻击。我看见它掉下去了！
Godzilla's Apex attack. I saw it go down!
你认为他再次出现是巧合吗
You think it's a coincidence that he reappears
碰巧摧毁了那个特定的设施？
and just so happens to destroy that specific facility?
哈哈，不，不，不，不。不是巧合。
Ha-ha, no, no, no, no. No such thing as coincidence.
爸爸，我告诉你，
[Madison] Dad, I'm telling you,
激怒了他，我们在这里看不到他。
provoking him that we're not seeing here.
不然哥斯拉为什么要炫耀恐吓呢
Why else would Godzilla flash an intimidation display
如果周围没有另一个泰坦？
if there wasn't another Titan around?
那个播客把你的脑袋塞满了垃圾。
That podcast is filling your head with garbage.
-你应该在学校。-我只是想帮忙。
-You should be in school. -I am just trying to help.
我不想你帮忙。我要你保持安全。
I don't want you to help. I want you to stay safe.
我们需要一个和平解决这些问题的计划，
We needed a plan to keep peace with these things,
最好的一个我们刚刚在火焰中倒下。
and the best one we had just went down in flames.
我没有了。
I don't have any more.
我最不需要担心的就是你。
And the last thing that I need is to be worrying about you.
哥斯拉救了我们。你和妈妈在一起。你看到了。
Godzilla saved us. You were there with Mom. You saw it.
你怎么能怀疑他？
How could you doubt him?
-一定有规律。-没有。
-There has to be a pattern. -There doesn't.
-他被激怒的原因。-没有。
-A reason why he was provoked. -There isn't.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
因为生物，像人一样，可以改变。
Because creatures, like people, can change.
现在，哥斯拉在外面
And right now, Godzilla's out there
他在伤害别人，我们不知道为什么。
and he's hurting people, and we don't know why.
所以你可以放松一下吗？
So cut your pop some slack, would ya?
爸爸，家里见。
See you at home, Dad.
你想知道我的理论吗？
[Bernie]  You wanna know my theory?
我是说，你当然知道。所以你才在这里。
I mean, of course you do. That's why you're here.
拜托，这都是关于模式和变量的。
Come on, it's all about patterns and variables.
哦，等等，跟我来。我要带你回去
Oh, wait, stick with me. I'm gonna take you back
带着这个上六年级，好吗？
to sixth grade with this, okay?
哥斯拉被激怒时会攻击，这就是模式。
Godzilla attacks when provoked, that's the pattern.
彭萨科拉是唯一的海岸顶点枢纽
Pensacola is the only coastal Apex hub
先进的机器人实验室。
with an advanced robotics lab.
这就是变量。
That's the variable.
把它们加起来，你的答案是
And add them up and your answer is
这个顶点是问题的核心。
that Apex is at the heart of the problem.
-[微弱的哔哔声]-[门关上]
-[faint beep] -[door closes]
我能帮助你吗？
Can I help you?
如果你想预约，
If you want an appointment,
我的办公时间是九点到五点。
my office hours are nine to five.
-求你了，林德医生。-怎么回事。。。
-[Walter] Please, Dr. Lind. -What the f...
像你我这样的人，
Guys like you and me,
我们不做正常的工作，是吗？
we don't do normal hours, do we?
我一直盯着空洞的地球
I've been fixated on Hollow Earth
只要你有。
for as long as you have.
你说这里是所有泰坦的诞生地
Your theory that it's the birthplace of all Titans
很吸引人。
is fascinating.
你的书令人印象深刻。
Your book was very impressive.
哦，是吗？嗯，我有大约30箱没卖出去
Oh, yeah? Well, I got about 30 unsold boxes
如果你想的话就在我的公寓里。
in my apartment if you want some.
[咯咯笑]
[chuckles]
沃尔特·西蒙斯。
Walt Simmons.
我知道你是谁，先生。很荣幸。
I know who you are, sir. It's an honor.
不，荣誉是我的。这就是紧迫性。
No, the honor is mine. As is the urgency.
哥斯拉从来没有无缘无故地袭击过我们。
Godzilla has never attacked us unprovoked before.
现在是危险时期，林德医生。
These are dangerous times, Dr. Lind.
请允许我介绍一下
Allow me to introduce
我们的首席技术官任泽泽先生。
our Apex chief technology officer, Mr. Ren Serizawa.
他有件有趣的事要给你看。
He has an interesting thing to show you.
[嘟嘟声]
[beeps]
我们的一颗新卫星的磁成像。
Magnetic imaging from one of our new satellites.
你知道这是什么，对吧？
You know what this is, right?
空心地球。
[Nathan] Hollow Earth.
[沃尔特]像海洋一样广阔的生态系统，
[Walter] An ecosystem as vast as any ocean,
就在我们脚下。
right beneath our feet.
这个能量信号是巨大的。
This energy signal is enormous.
和Gojira的读数几乎一样。
And almost identical to readings from  Gojira.
[沃尔特]太阳为地球表面提供燃料，
[Walter] As our sun fuels the planet's surface,
这种能量支撑着空洞的地球，
this energy sustains the Hollow Earth,
让生命像我们的泰坦朋友一样强大。
enabling life as powerful as our aggressive Titan friend.
如果我们能驾驭这种生命力，
If we can harness this life force,
我们会有一个能和哥斯拉竞争的武器。
we'll have a weapon that can compete with Godzilla.
我需要你帮忙找到它。
I need your help to find it.
[咯咯笑]
[chuckling]
我不知道我是否适合这份工作。
I don't know if I'm the right guy for the job.
你看过评论了吗？
Did you read the reviews?
“一个从事边缘物理交易的科幻庸医。”
"A sci-fi quack trading in fringe physics."
看看他们把我的办公室放哪儿了。
Look where they put my office.
我就在长笛课对面的地下室。
I'm in the basement right across from flute class.
再说了，我已经不跟Monarch在一起了。
Besides, I'm not with Monarch anymore.
空心地球是不可能进入的。
And Hollow Earth entry is impossible.
我们试过了。
We tried.
你哥哥的事我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about your brother.
他是个真正的开拓者。
He was a true pioneer.
谢谢。
Thanks.
[吸气，清嗓子]
[sniffles, clears throat]
看，我们所有的正向扫描
See, all of our forward scans
建议那里有一个适宜居住的环境。
suggest a habitable environment down there.
那么，你哥哥的任务到底出了什么问题？
So, what really went wrong on your brother's mission?
当他们试图进入时，
When they tried to enter,
他们遇到了引力反转。
they hit a gravitational inversion.
整个星球的引力
A whole planet's worth of gravity
瞬间逆转。
reversed in a split second.
他们瞬间就被碾碎了。
They were crushed in an instant.
如果我告诉你我们在顶点，
What if I told you that we, at Apex,
创造了一种非凡的工艺
have created a phenomenal craft
哪一个能维持这样的反转？
which could sustain such an inversion?
空心地球飞行器。
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicle.
举起来。
HEAV.
我们可以去旅行
We can make the journey
有可能挖空地球，林德博士。
to Hollow Earth possible, Dr. Lind.
但我们需要你来领导这次任务。
But we need you to lead the mission.
帮助我。
Help me.
帮助所有人。
Help everyone.
大海捞针
Finding this needle in a haystack
是我们对哥斯拉最好的射门。
is our best shot against Godzilla.
嗯，我，呃，可能有个主意。
Well, I, uh, might have an idea.
但这太疯狂了。
But it's crazy.
我喜欢疯狂的想法。他们使我富有。
I love crazy ideas. They made me rich.
你们熟悉基因记忆吗？
[Nathan] Are you guys familiar with genetic memory?
所有的泰坦都有一个共同的冲动
It's a theory that all Titans share a common impulse
回到进化的源头。
to return to their evolutionary source.
就像产卵的鲑鱼。
Like spawning salmon.
确切地。或者。。。或者信鸽。
Exactly. Or a... Or a homing pigeon.
如果这是泰坦的家
So if this is the Titans' home
这股生命力支撑着他们。。。
and this life force sustains them...
泰坦可以给你指路。
A Titan could show you the way.
[内森]是的。
[Nathan] Yeah.
在一位老同事的帮助下。
With a little help of an old colleague.
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
呃，在哪？
[Ilene] Ugh, where is it?
安德鲁斯医生，你有客人
[receptionist]  Dr. Andrews, you have a visitor
[手语]
[in sign language]
好的。
[sighs] Okay.
[轻声笑]
[chuckles softly]
[雷声隆隆]
[thunder rumbles]
[伊琳]地洞里的电源？
[Ilene] A power source in Hollow Earth?
这听起来很疯狂，内森，甚至对你来说。
This sounds nuts, Nathan, even for you.
[内森]在那里！我们只需要孔带我们去！
[Nathan] It's there! We just need Kong to bring us to it!
[Ilene]一旦你把孔带出安全壳，
[Ilene] The second you take Kong out of containment,
哥斯拉会来找他的。
Godzilla's gonna come for him.
[内森]你说过你不能永远把他留在这里。
[Nathan] You said you can't keep him here forever.
不，我们的干涉已经造成了严重的破坏
No. Our meddling has already wreaked havoc
在香港的栖息地。
on Kong's habitat.
我不可能让你拖他
No way am I letting you drag him
把他当作武器。
halfway across the world to use him as a weapon.
不，不是作为武器。作为盟友。
[Nathan] No, not as a weapon. As an ally.
为了保护我们，带路下去。
To protect us, lead the way down there.
你凭什么认为他会进去？
What even makes you think that he'll go in?
你一直相信骷髅岛
You always believed that Skull Island
就像空心的地球浮出水面，对吗？
was like Hollow Earth come to the surface, right?
孔的祖先就是从这里来的。
And that's where Kong's ancestors came from.
嗯，嗯。
Mm-hmm.
穿过南极洲的入口，
Through the entrance in Antarctica,
我们可以帮他找个新家。
we could help him find a new home.
他可以救我们。
And he could save ours.
她的。
Hers.
那是我们唯一的希望。
That power source may be our only hope.
我们得阻止哥斯拉。这是我们唯一的机会。
We gotta stop Godzilla. This is our only chance.
我们必须接受。
We have to take it.
[动物的叽叽喳喳声]
[creatures chittering]
[电的噼啪声和嗡嗡声]
[electrical crackling and humming]
[叹息声]
[sighs]
-好吧。-是的！
-Okay. -Yes!
但说到香港，我说的都是事实。
But when it comes to Kong, what I say goes.
你说出术语。非常感谢。
You name the terms. Thank you.
对不起的。非常感谢。
Sorry. Thank you.
你不会后悔的。
You won't regret this.
-嗯，我已经后悔了。-[砰砰声]
-Mm, I already regret this. -[thudding]
[叹息声]
[sighs]
[手语]
[in sign language]
[伊琳叹息]
[Ilene sighs]
来吧。
[exhales heavily] Come on.
[播放乡村歌曲]
[country song playing]
如果你现在能见到我
♪ If you could see me now ♪
“那个说他宁愿流浪的人”
♪ The one who said that he'd rather roam ♪
“那个说他宁愿一个人待着的人”
♪ The one who said he'd rather be alone ♪
如果你现在能见到我
♪ If you could only see me now ♪
我在风中待的太久了
♪ I've been too long in the wind ♪
在雨中太久了
♪ Too long in the rain ♪
[模糊的无线电谈话]
[indistinct radio chatter]
尽我所能的安慰
♪ Taking any comfort that I can ♪
“回首往事，渴望”
♪ Looking back and longing for ♪
我锁链的自由。。。♪
♪ The freedom of my chains... ♪
[门砰的一声，蜂鸣器响]
[door thuds, buzzer sounds]
喔！天哪，我能从上面闻到他的味道。
Whoo! Jeez, I can smell him from up here.
他也能闻到你。
Well, he can smell you, too.
[孔呻吟]
[Kong moaning]
还是不是粉丝？
Still not a fan, huh?
[手语]
[in sign language]
她在说什么？
What's she saying?
只是一个Iwi表达。
Just an Iwi expression.
意思是你很勇敢。
It means that you're very brave.
-是吗？-[伊琳]嗯。
-Yeah? -[Ilene] Mm-hmm.
[内森]嘿，用点镇静剂。
[Nathan] Hey, use a light touch on the sedatives.
他是我们的护卫。
He's our escort.
我们不能让他在我们到达地洞时昏迷。
We can't have him comatose when we reach Hollow Earth.
如果孔不愿意去呢？
What if Kong doesn't go willingly?
-那你怎么办？-[喇叭声]
-What do you do then? -[PA chimes]
林德医生，请报告
[woman on PA] Dr. Lind, please report
去前甲板。林德医生。
to the forward deck. Dr. Lind.
请原谅我。
Excuse me.
新来的。
New arrivals.
[手语]
[in sign language]
-[金属吱吱声]-[孔咕噜声]
-[metal creaks] -[Kong grunting]
[低声咆哮]
[growls softly]
欢迎光临。
Welcome.
真 的。想出这个主意的白痴是谁？
Wow. Who's the idiot who came up with this idea?
-哈哈。-我是玛雅·西蒙斯。
-Ha-ha. -I'm Maia Simmons.
我父亲派我来的。
My father sent me.
我跑向顶点。
I run point for Apex.
内森·林德，任务负责人。
Nathan Lind, mission chief.
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growls]
是的，别担心。我只是来照顾孩子的。
Yeah, don't worry. I'm just here to babysit.
-[孔咆哮]-[金属叮当声]
-[Kong growls] -[metal clangs]
空心地球飞行器
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicles
正在去南极洲的路上。
are on their way to Antarctica as we speak.
我知道你们认为自己很前卫，
I know you people think you're cutting-edge,
但我们借给你的这些原型
but these prototypes we're loaning you
会让你一直在飞的东西看起来像用过的Miatas。
will make what you've been flying look like used Miatas.
我爱米亚塔斯。
I love Miatas.
忘了价格标签吧，那当然是淫秽的。
Forget about the price tag, which is obscene, of course.
单靠反重力引擎就能产生
The antigravity engines alone produce
足够维加斯一周的照明费。
enough charge to light up Vegas for a week.
给人留下深刻印象吧。
Feel free to be impressed.
真 的。
Wow.
[雷声隆隆]
[thunder crashes]
[呻吟声]
[moaning]
[内森]好吧，我们会的
[Nathan] All right, we'll be
48小时后到达南极洲入口。
at the Antarctica entry in 48 hours.
这条路会把我们带进空心的地球。
This path will get us into Hollow Earth.
一旦我们进去，孔应该带我们找到电源。
Once we're inside, Kong should lead us to the power source.
现在，重力反演
Now, the gravitational inversion
会很紧张。
will be quite intense.
我们最好的猜测是在进入时，
Our best guess is that on entry,
感觉就像蹦极。。。
it'll feel like bungee jumping...
把绳子绑在你的小肠上。
with the cord tied to your lower intestine.
但如果你的直升机像你说的那么好。。。
But if your helicopters are as good as you say...
垂荡。
HEAVs.
如果你的起伏和你说的一样好，
If your HEAVs are as good as you say they are,
我相信我们能做到。
I believe we can do this.
他们会做好的。
[Maia] They'll do the job.
你只要做你自己的。
You just gotta do yours.
杰出的。
Excellent.
安德鲁斯医生。
[Wilcox] Dr. Andrews.
我们避开了所有哥斯拉的
We've avoided all of Godzilla's
根据你的指导方针。
according to your guidelines.
很好。
Good.
我需要担心吗？
Do I need to be concerned?
对。他们确实有办法感知威胁。
Yes. They do have a way of sensing threats.
我们相信他们有一个古老的竞争。
And we believe that they had an ancient rivalry.
传说他们的祖先
The myths say that their ancestors
在一场大战中互相厮杀。
fought each other in a great war.
如果他们再见面，谁向谁鞠躬，是吗？
So if they meet again, who bows to who, is that it?
[嘲笑]
[scoffs]
不，我在那个岛上花了10年时间研究他。
No, I spent 10 years on that island studying him.
我肯定知道。
I know this for sure.
孔不向任何人鞠躬。
Kong bows to no one.
[微弱、低沉的呻吟声]
[faint, muffled moaning]
[微弱的脉冲声]
[muffled pulsing]
[脉搏加快]
[pulsing quickening]
[雨声]
[rain pattering]
[砰的一声]
[loud thud]
她应该在外面吗？
Is she supposed to be out there?
-[砰砰声继续]-[金属声]
-[thudding continues] -[metallic whining]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[微弱、低沉的咆哮声]
[faint, muffled roaring]
[微弱、低沉的咕噜声]
[faint, muffled grunting]
【孔小声咕哝】
[Kong grunts softly]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong moaning]
贾，来吧。来吧。
Jia, come on. Come on.
[手语]
[in sign language]
[怒火]
[huffs]
[呻吟声]
[moaning]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunting softly]
[呻吟声]
[groaning]
猴子刚才说话了吗？
Did the monkey just talk?
好了，同学们，听好了。
[Bernie on speaker] Okay, class, listen up.
在哥斯拉袭击彭萨科拉峰的过程中，
In the midst of Godzilla's attack on Apex Pensacola,
我发现了一些没有官方分类的疯狂技术。
I found some crazy tech with no official classification.
我看到的不一致
What I saw doesn't match
我见过的任何工程规范。
any of the engineering specs I've ever seen.
那么，他们在这么秘密的停电下干什么，嗯？
So what are they working on in such blackout secrecy, hmm?
这可能是最终解开的线索
This could be the thread that finally unravels
阴谋的顶点。
the Apex sweater of conspiracy.
你最好相信我会继续努力。
You better believe I'm gonna keep tugging.
现在，我很安全。
For now, I'm secure.
隐姓埋名
Anonymous and hiding in plain sight
当我继续我的使命。
as I continue my mission.
[“触犯法律”在货车扬声器上大声喊叫]
["Breaking The Law" blaring on van speaker]
“违法，违法”
♪ Breaking the law Breaking the law ♪
[音乐停止]
[music stops]
说清楚点，我哥哥永远不会知道我们拿走了他的货车。
To be clear, my brother can never know we took his van.
乔希，说清楚，即使我们出了事故，
Josh, to be clear, even if we got into an accident,
我想他看不出来。
I don't think he could tell.
不，不，我哥哥也不会让你开车的。
No, no, my brother would never let you drive either.
我的使命，我的方向盘。
My mission, my wheel.
我只是觉得这不是个好主意，
I just don't think it's a good idea,
在网上寻找一些神秘的怪人。
looking for some secret weirdo off the Internet.
我是说，我们刚刚就这件事举行了一次集会。
I mean, we just had an assembly about this.
他不是怪人。他是个秘密调查员。
He's not a weirdo. He's a covert investigator.
他是唯一一个寻找真相的人
And he's the only one looking for the truth
关于哥斯拉和顶点。
about Godzilla and Apex.
所以让他看看。我们为什么要帮助他？
So let him look. Why do we have to help him?
因为。。。
[sighs] Because...
如果我们不这样做，其他人也不会。
If we don't, nobody else will.
你来不来？
Are you coming or not?
显然我要来了。
Obviously I'm coming.
[货车门嘎嘎作响]
[van door rattles]
它卡住了。
It's stuck.
-[引擎转速]-等等，等等，等等，等等！
-[engine revs] -Wait, wait, wait, wait!
精神控制。
[Bernie on speaker] Mind control.
灵能连接技术是现实。
Psionic link technology is a reality.
这是正确的。一个大脑控制另一个。
That's right. One brain controlling another.
哦，伙计。
Oh, man.
[伯尼]想象一下，在全球范围内
[Bernie]  Imagine that on a global scale
阿派克是不可战胜的。
and Apex is invincible.
我们听这个怪人讲了好几个小时了。
We've been listening to this weirdo for hours.
-[麦迪逊]哇，哇，哇！-[轮胎尖叫声]
-[Madison] Whoa, whoa, whoa! -[tires screech]
哇！住手！
Whoa! Knock it off!
等等，这就是我跟你说的部分。
Wait, this is the part I was telling you about.
[伯尼]…需要特别的紫外线才能知道你被标记了！
[Bernie]  ...need special UV to even know you've been marked!
一两加仑也不行。
One or two gallons won't cut it.
我需要大量的漂白剂！
I need my bleach in bulk!
因为间谍灰尘是真的，伙计们！
Because spy dust is real, people!
我是说，拜托，肉眼看不见。。。
I mean, come on, invisible to the naked eye...
-[关掉音响]-我们就是这样找到他的。
-[turns off stereo] -That's how we find him.
-漂白剂。-漂白剂？
-The bleach. -Bleach?
他消耗了一吨漂白剂。
He consumes a ton of bleach.
他喝漂白剂？
He drinks bleach?
用它洗澡。
Showers with it.
哦！是的，我用漂白剂洗澡。不，什么？
Oh! Yeah, I shower with bleach. No, what?
有机追踪技术的预防。
Prevention against organic tracking technology.
看到了吗？手艺。
See? Tradecraft.
如果他喝了就更有意义了。
Would've made more sense if he just drank it.
来吧，再来一个地方。
[Madison] Come on, just one more place.
麦迪逊，这太老了。
Madison, this is getting old.
嘿，你卖漂白剂？
Hey, you sell bleach?
这又是一个互联网挑战吗？
Is this another one of those Internet challenge things?
当我把洗衣粉卖给那些孩子的时候，
When I sold those kids those detergent pods,
我不知道他们会吃。
I didn't know they were gonna eat them.
我还在处理那些诉讼。
I'm still dealing with the lawsuits from that.
听着，我们在找一个人
Look, we're looking for a guy
他在Apex控制论公司工作。
who works for Apex Cybernetics.
买了很多漂白剂。就像每天晚上一样。
Buys a lot of bleach. Like every night.
他可能是偏执狂，
He's probably paranoid,
紧张，不喜欢日光。
high-strung, doesn't like daylight.
你知道，他的胡子上有很多碎屑，
You know, has a lot of crumbs in his beard,
如果他有胡子。
if he has a beard.
好吧，听着，你们要糖果吗？
Okay, look, you kids want some candy?
因为我可以帮你拿糖果。
Because I can help you with candy.
看着我的眼睛。可以？我需要信息。
Look at me in the eye. Okay? I need information.
是的，我们要很多糖果。
Yeah, we want lots of candy.
你在做什么？你觉得。。。？
What are you doing? You think...?
哦，你是说伯尼。
Oh, you mean Bernie.
是的，我认识那个人。
Yeah, I know that guy.
他买了一吨漂白剂。
He buys, like, a ton of bleach.
我也知道他在哪。
I know where he is, too.
如果你买活鱼，我会告诉你他的地址。
If you buy a live fish, I'll give you his address.
[敲门声]
[banging on door]
伯尼？
[Madison] Bernie?
[伯尼]先生。。。[清嗓子]不。。。
[Bernie] Mister... [clears throat] Mis...
-[砰]-[伯尼呻吟]
-[thud] -[Bernie groans]
伯尼先生不在家。
[in deep voice] Mister Bernie not home.
是的，那绝对是伯尼先生。
Yep, that was definitely Mister Bernie.
是 啊。嗯。。。
Yeah. Um...
你好！你好。听着，我们想谈谈Apex和哥斯拉。
Hi! Hi. Listen, we wanna talk about Apex and Godzilla.
不，不，不。
[Bernie] No. No. No.
我。。。我看到你的脸了。我联系当局。对。
I... I got your faces. I contact authorities. Yes.
因为敲门？
[Josh] For knocking on a door?
不，不。
[Bernie chuckles] No. No.
伯尼，你不相信当局。
Bernie, you don't trust the authorities.
我叫麦迪逊·拉塞尔。
My name is Madison Russell.
我父亲为君王工作而我母亲。。。
My father works for Monarch and my mother was...
艾玛·拉塞尔，对吧？
Emma Russell, right?
在我们继续之前，我有一个问题。
Before we go any farther, I got one question.
水龙头还是不水龙头？
Tap or no tap?
没有水龙头。
No tap.
-打扰一下，“水龙头”是什么？-水。
-Excuse me, what is "tap"? -Water.
他们在里面放了氟化物。是从纳粹那里学来的。
They put fluoride in it. Learned it from the Nazis.
理论上说，它让你变得温顺，易于操纵。
Theory is it makes you docile, easy to manipulate.
哦，我喝自来水。
Oh, I drink tap water.
是的，我有点想。
Yeah, I kind of figured that.
但她为你们俩着想，
But she does the thinking for both of you,
所以应该没事。
so it should be all right.
-谢谢。-好吧。
-Thanks. -Okay.
你有什么发现？
What you got?
我相信哥斯拉最近的袭击
I believe Godzilla's most recent attacks
不仅仅是随机的。
haven't just been random.
我想他瞄准了Apex工厂。
I think he targeted the Apex facility.
我的意见是一样的。
I'm of the same opinion.
但为什么呢？什么事激怒了他？
But why? What is Apex up to that's provoking him?
五年来，我一直在这家公司工作，
For five years, I embedded myself inside this company,
想弄清楚他们的游戏是什么。
trying to figure out what their game was.
然后，上周。。。
Then, last week...
我看到这个了。
I saw this.
一份巨大货物的舱单从这里寄来
A manifest of huge cargo being sent from here
前往香港总部
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong,
这毫无意义
which makes no sense
因为我们没有重型运输设备。
because we are not equipped for heavy shipping.
-然后呢？-然后砰！
-Then what? -And then boom!
哥斯拉出现了。
Godzilla shows up.
一半的设施倒塌了，
Caved in half the facility,
但我偷看了一些可疑的技术
but I got a sneak peek at some suspicious tech
藏在一个秘密地堡里。
which was hidden in a secret bunker.
我是说，一些可疑的技术人员。
I mean, some pretty damn suspicious tech.
是啊，那是什么？
Yeah, but what is that?
那是，呃。。。
That's, um...
那是Katzunari单麦芽威士忌。
That's Katzunari single malt whiskey.
是的，但它在枪套里。
Yeah, but it's in a gun holster.
这是我莎拉送的礼物。
It was a gift from my Sara.
你有莎拉吗？
You have a Sara?
她是我妻子。
She was my wife.
呃，她去世了。
Um, she passed on.
[伯尼叹息]
[Bernie sighs]
她是我的磐石。
She was my rock.
我的真相。
My truth.
我告诉你一件事，当这一天变得空虚，
I'll tell you something, the day that this goes empty,
那一天你知道我已经放弃了。
that's the day you know I've given up.
伯尼。
[Madison] Bernie.
我想我们可以互相帮助。
I think we can help each other.
好吧，我想既然我们是一个团队，
Okay, I guess now that we're a team,
我觉得我们应该想出一个计划。
I feel like we should come up with a plan.
我们正在进入顶点。
We're breaking into Apex.
-等等，什么？-[伯尼]你听到了。
-[Josh] Wait, what? -[Bernie] You heard her.
自来水。
Tap water.
倒霉。
Shit.
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[满意地咕哝]
[grunts contentedly]
[伊琳]嘿。
[Ilene] Hey.
[手语]
[in sign language]
非常感谢。
Thank you.
她怎么样了？
How is she?
冷静。太冷静了，太可怕了。[咯咯笑]
Calm. So calm, it's scary. [chuckles]
那真是非同寻常。
That was extraordinary.
我一直在签字母表。基本命令。
I have been signing the alphabet. Basic commands.
我以为他表现出认可，但他从来没有。。。
I thought that he showed recognition, but he never...
你知道他们沟通多久了吗？
Do you have any idea how long they've been communicating?
不。
No.
我知道他们有关系。
I knew that they had a bond.
他信任她。
He trusts her.
如果没有她，他会把船搞得四分五裂。
Without her, he'd be tearing the ship apart.
你知道，贾的父母是在岛上被杀的。
You know, Jia's parents were killed on the island.
当暴风雨席卷全岛时，
When the storm took over the island,
它消灭了当地人。
it wiped out the native people.
但孔救了她。
But Kong saved her.
她无处可去。
She had nowhere to go.
所以我答应了，
So I made a promise,
为了保护她。
then and there, to protect her.
我想在某种程度上，他也是这么做的。
And I think that in some way, he did the same.
你认为他会听从她的指示吗？
Do you think he would take directions from her?
不。
No.
如果有人能控制香港。。。
If we have someone who can keep the reins on Kong...
是啊，没人能控制住孔。
Yeah, no one can keep the reins on Kong.
她还是个孩子。
And she's a child.
[遥远的，微弱的脉冲声]
[distant, muffled pulsing]
[低沉的呻吟声]
[muffled groaning]
[内森]我知道贾只是个孩子。
[Nathan] I know Jia is only a child.
但她是他唯一可以交流的人。
But she's the only one he'll communicate with.
我们需要孔找到电源。
And we need Kong to find that power source.
世界需要他。
The world needs him.
[警报声]
[alarm blaring]
[低沉的呻吟声]
[muffled moaning]
[含糊不清的喊叫]
[indistinct shouting]
她在说什么？
What's she saying?
哥斯拉。
Godzilla.
[咆哮声]
[roaring]
[紧急谈话]
[urgent chatter]
-[孔咕噜声]-[金属叮当声]
-[Kong grunts] -[metal clangs]
我们改变路线了吗？
Did we change course?
不，我们离你标记的区域很远。
No. We're nowhere near the areas you flagged.
看来他是来找我们的。
It looks like he's coming for us anyway.
他不会来找我们的。
[Ilene] He's not coming for us.
他？那就甩了他。把猴子扔了！
Him? Then dump him. Dump the monkey!
不如我们把你扔了，嗯？
How about we throw you off instead, huh?
[咆哮声]
[roars]
我们必须释放他。
We have to release him.
如果我们失去了金刚，任务就结束了。
If we lose Kong, the mission is over.
他是个坐以待毙的人。
He's a sitting duck out there.
我们必须让他保护自己。还有我们。
We have to let him protect himself. And us.
[武器发射]
[weapons firing]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[roaring]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[尖叫声]
[screams]
[咆哮声]
[roaring]
[高声咆哮]
[high-pitched roar]
[咆哮声]
[roaring]
[roars]
[男人尖叫]
[men scream]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[哥斯拉呻吟]
[Godzilla groans]
哦，天哪，贾！
[Ilene] Oh, my God, Jia!
内森？
Nathan?
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[大叫]
[yelling]
[都咆哮着]
[both snarling]
[警报声]
[alarm beeping]
[咆哮声]
[growling]
[roaring]
[呻吟声]
[moans]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[roaring]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[哥斯拉的尖叫声]
[Godzilla screeching]
[尖叫声]
[screeches]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong moans]
[电悸动]
[electrical throbbing]
[哥斯拉尖叫声]
[Godzilla screeches]
他需要我们的帮助。
He needs our help.
一定有办法迷惑哥斯拉。
There must be some way to disorient Godzilla.
深水炸弹。
Depth charges.
[蜂鸣器鸣响]
[buzzer sounding]
[咆哮声]
[snarling]
[咆哮，大叫]
[growls, yells]
[低沉的爆炸声]
[muffled explosion]
[干呕]
[retches]
[咳嗽]
[coughing]
[内森]他绕回来了。
[Nathan] He's circling back.
只有他们中的一个提交了才能结束。
This won't end until one of them submits.
[轻轻呻吟]
[groaning softly]
-[内森]关掉它。-什么？
-[Nathan] Shut it down. -What?
所有的一切。
All of it.
枪，引擎。
Guns, engines.
-把它关掉。马上。-如果我们那样做，我们就死定了。
-Shut it down. Right now. -If we do that, we're dead.
不，我们在装死。
No, we're playing dead.
我们让他觉得他赢了。
And we're making him think that he's won.
[麦克风呜呜声]
[mic whines]
切断电源。关掉引擎。
Cut the power. Cut the engines.
杀死任何发出噪音的东西。
Kill anything that makes a noise.
[电源关闭]
[power shutting down]
[寂静降临]
[silence descends]
这个更好用。
This better work.
[手语]
[in sign language]
[微弱地呻吟]
[moans weakly]
我们一走，他就会回来的。
[Ilene] As soon as we move, he'll be back.
剩下的路怎么走？
How are we supposed to get the rest of the way?
香港的身高怎么样？
How's Kong with heights?
那么，计划是什么？
So, what's the plan?
[伯尼]我们查一下33层的内容。
[Bernie] We find out what's on Sublevel 33.
-[酒瓶叮当声]-[乔希]噢。
-[bottle clinks] -[Josh] Ow.
继续开，自来水。
Keep it moving, tap water.
前进。
Go ahead.
[喘息声]
[panting]
好吧，疯帽匠。在兔子洞里。
All right, Mad Hatter. Down the rabbit hole.
可以。我们知道了。
Okay. We got this.
哦，天哪！
Oh, my God!
[乔希]你确定我们能相信这个人吗？
[Josh] Are you sure we can trust this guy?
是啊，为什么？
Yeah, why?
嗯，主要是因为他总是说些疯狂的废话
Well, mainly because he says crazy shit all the time
带着一瓶威士忌
and carries a bottle of whiskey
像枪一样从他死去的妻子身上。
from his dead wife like a gun.
我觉得很浪漫。
I think it's romantic.
呜呼！
Whoo-hoo!
我真的不懂女人。
I really don't understand women.
[咕哝声]
[grunts]
好吧，来吧。
Okay, come on.
-[电的噼啪声]-[喘息声]
-[electricity crackling] -[gasps]
[伯尼]整件事都发生了，还有这个。。。
[Bernie] This whole thing came down, and there was this...
眼睛。
eye.
我们在看什么？
[Josh] Uh, what are we looking at?
[伯尼]不，不，不，不。不，它在这里。
[Bernie] No, no, no, no. No, it was here.
我向上帝发誓，那是。。。就在那里。
I swear to God, it was... it was right there.
嘿，伙计们。
Hey, guys.
-[按钮蜂鸣]-[门蜂鸣]
-[button beeps] -[door buzzes]
有人知道这条路通向哪里吗？
Anyone know where this leads to?
你相信我，对吧？
You believe me, right?
因为我知道这里有些东西。
'Cause I know that there was something here.
[乔希]手电筒会让我偏头痛的。
[Josh] I'm gonna get a migraine from that torch.
“次级”这东西有多深，伯尼？
"Sublevel." How deep does this thing go, Bernie?
地狱。去死吧。
Hell. Goes to hell.
[女声]33级。
[female automated voice] Sublevel 33.
[男自动语音]磁浮班车出发
[male automated voice] Maglev shuttle departure
9点到新墨西哥州的罗斯威尔。
to Roswell, New Mexico at 0900 hours.
[机械呜呜声]
[mechanical whine]
[乔希]哇。[咯咯笑]
[Josh] Whoa. [chuckles]
[模糊PA公告]
[indistinct PA announcement]
这是什么？
What is all this?
这是分离的文明。
It's breakaway civilization.
我是说，来吧。这是第一页
I mean, come on. This is page one
在顶点玩上帝手册。嗯？
in the Apex-playing-God handbook. Huh?
我是说，光照派经营着影子经济
I mean, the Illuminati running shadow economies
所有这些都是为了给精英们提供一个隐蔽的殖民地
all to fund a hidden colony for the elite
如果这些政府
in case any of these governments
和大公司
and megacorporations
不小心按下了世界末日按钮。
accidentally hit the doomsday button.
这是有道理的
It makes sense
-如果你仔细想想。-是的，当然。
-if you think about it. -Yeah, sure.
[含糊不清的喊叫]
[indistinct shouting]
-[麦迪逊]有人来了。-什么？
-[Madison] Someone's coming. -What?
-有人来了。-什么？
-Someone's coming. -What?
-有人来了？-[麦迪逊]是的！
-[Josh] Someone's coming? -[Madison] Yes!
哦，天哪。
Oh, my God.
[低沉的声音]
[muffled squelching]
-它们看起来像鸡蛋。-骷髅爬虫。
-[Josh] They look like eggs. -Skull-crawlers.
Apex在用骷髅爬行动物做什么？
What's Apex doing with skull-crawlers?
好吧，我们把它装好！
[man] All right, let's load it up!
-[尖叫声]-[警报声]
-[screams] -[alarm blares]
[伯尼]那是什么？那是什么？
[Bernie] What was that? What was that?
-[引擎嗡嗡声]-不可能。不，不，不。来吧。
-[engine humming] -No way. No, no, no. Come on.
好了，伙计们，我想我们要走了。
Okay, guys, I think we're moving.
上面说我们要走了
It says we're headed
前往香港总部。
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong.
-什么？[伯尼]香港。
-What? -[Bernie] Hong Kong.
这意味着我们会得到一些答案。
That means that we're gonna get some answers.
G10，准备发射。
[automated voice] G10, clear for launch.
[引擎声]
[engine thrumming]
[发动机加速]
[engine accelerating]
我们开始吧。
Here we go.
[微弱的脉冲声]
[muffled pulsing]
我们快到了！
We're getting close!
-[模糊的无线电谈话]-[警报声]
-[indistinct radio chatter] -[alarm blaring]
[线束折断]
[harnesses snapping]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
[呻吟声]
[moans]
[好奇地咕哝]
[grunting curiously]
[风吹口哨]
[wind whistling]
【孔小声咕哝】
[Kong grunting softly]
[手语]
[in sign language]
[呻吟声]
[moans]
[鼻塞声]
[snuffles]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
[呼噜声]
[snorts]
没用了。
It's not working.
等等。等等，等等，等等。
Just wait. Wait, wait, wait.
如果她告诉他呢
What if she tells him
下面还有像他这样的人吗？
there are others down there like him?
但你不知道。
But you don't know that.
我们失去了整个舰队。
We lost our entire fleet getting here.
他没有退路了。
There's no way back for him.
他在这里活不下去了。
And he can't survive here.
[低声咆哮]
[growls softly]
[呻吟声]
[moaning]
好吧。好吧。
All right. All right.
[轻轻地]嘿。
[softly] Hey.
[手语]
[in sign language]
[叹息声]
[sighs]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
[咆哮声]
[snarls]
他要走了。准备发射！每个人都到他们的车站去。
He's going. Prepare to launch! Everybody to their station.
我们得走了。
We gotta go.
所有机组人员都安全了
[man on PA] All flights crews cleared
立即进行垂荡发射。
for immediate HEAV launch.
[飞行员1]升沉1在线。我们准备发射了。
[pilot 1]  HEAV 1 online. We're clear for launch.
[控制]收到，升1。
[control]  Copy that, HEAV 1.
[飞行员2]升沉2在线。马上离开机库。
[pilot 2]  HEAV 2 online. Exiting hangar now.
[控制]垂荡2，确认4055。
[control]  HEAV 2, confirmation 4055.
[pilot 3]我是Heav3在线，正在发射。
[pilot 3]  This is HEAV 3 online, launching now.
我们从后面跟着他。
We'll follow him from behind.
在那里。
There.
他来了。
There he is.
[模糊的无线电谈话]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[发动机转速]
[engine revving]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
你确定猴子能活下来吗？
Are you sure the monkey's gonna survive this?
哦，他会没事的。我担心的是我们。
Oh, he'll be fine. It's us I'd worry about.
我们将在两秒内发射1000英里
We're about to be launched 1,000 miles in two seconds
直到地心引力倒转，把我们甩成自由落体。
until gravity inverts itself and spits us into free fall.
这将是你见过的最令人惊奇的事情。
It'll be the most amazing thing you've ever seen.
[隆隆声]
[rumbling]
在这里。为了呕吐物。
Here. For the vomit.
什么？
What?
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong groans]
[玛雅尖叫，气喘吁吁]
[Maia yelps, panting]
[警报声]
[alarm blaring]
[孔啸]
[Kong roaring]
[寂静降临]
[silence descends]
[咕噜声]
[grunting]
[扭曲的尖叫声]
[distorted screaming]
[自动语音]发动机故障，重力低。
[automated voice] Engine failure, gravity low.
-发动机故障。-[警报声]
-Engine failure. -[alarm blaring]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growls]
[警报声]
[alarms blaring]
[尖叫声]
[screaming]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong groans]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
全三角洲，反重力推进！[尖叫声]
All Delta, reverse gravity propulsion! [screams]
[生物的尖叫声]
[creatures screeching]
[玛雅喘息]
[Maia panting]
[生物的叫声]
[creature squawking]
[动物的叽叽喳喳声]
[creatures chittering]
很漂亮。
It's beautiful.
我是三号舱，
[pilot on radio] This is HEAV 3,
我们收到一些奇怪的雷达信号。
we're getting some strange radar activity.
我们要绕回来。。。
We're gonna circle back and...
[喘息声]
[gasps]
[生物尖叫声]
[creature screeching]
[尖叫声]
[all screaming]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growling]
[生物尖叫声]
[creature screeching]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[snarling]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
德尔塔，准备进攻！
All Delta, prepare to attack!
[生物尖叫声]
[creature screeching]
[砰砰声]
[thudding]
[孔咕噜]
[Kong grunting]
[骨头嘎吱作响]
[bones crunching]
[生物尖叫声]
[creature screeching]
[喘息声]
[panting]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[咕噜声]
[grunting]
太恶心了。
That's gross.
[伊琳在广播中]孔在移动。
[Ilene on radio] Kong's on the move.
我们得走了。
We gotta go.
[动物的叽叽喳喳声]
[creatures chittering]
[咆哮声]
[growling]
他好像知道
[Nathan on radio] Well, he seems to know
哦，他肯定能动。
Oh, he certainly can move.
[砰的回声]
[thud echoes]
[岩石撞击声]
[rocks thudding]
[呜呜声]
[whines]
[悠扬的器乐演奏]
[mellow instrumental music playing]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
[呼呼声]
[whooshes]
[隆隆声]
[rumbling]
好吧，好吧。
Okay, okay.
令人毛骨悚然的单轨正在减速。
Creepy monorail is slowing down.
[广播员]注意：船舱到了。
[announcer on PA]  Attention: Shipping pod arriving.
[播音员用广东话重复]
[announcer repeating in Cantonese]
[快速嘟嘟声]
[rapid beeping]
[喇叭声]
[horn blares]
[自动语音含糊不清]
[automated voice speaking indistinctly]
[伯尼]好的。保持安静。跟着我。
[Bernie] Okay. Keep quiet. Follow me.
[门砰的一声]
[gate thuds]
我们要进去？
We're going in?
是 啊。
Yeah.
哦，不！
Oh, no!
每次，我发誓。门恨我们。
Every time, I swear. Doors hate us.
[伯尼]哦，是的。
[Bernie] Oh, yeah.
-[伯尼]啊！-哦，天哪！
-[Bernie] Aah! -[Madison] Oh, my God!
它太大了。太蠢了。
It's just so massive. It's so stupid.
那么，这是什么地方？
So, what is this place?
好吧，如果有一个公司友好的术语
Well, if there's a corporate-friendly term
我得说我们在里面。
I'd say we are in it.
[麦迪逊]哦，天哪，真臭。
[Madison] Oh, God, that stinks.
[警报声]
[alarm blaring]
那可不好。伯尼！
That's not good. Bernie!
我真的很讨厌这个地方。
[Bernie] I really hate this place.
[自动语音]注意：演示
[automated voice] Attention: Demonstration
再过一分钟。
in T-minus one minute.
所有人员远离该区域。
All personnel are to stay clear of the area.
[机器通电]
[machines powering up]
[工程师]西蒙斯先生，系统正在上线。
[engineer] Mr. Simmons, systems are coming online now.
[呼气]
[exhales]
[金属叮当声]
[metal clanking]
开始上行。
Commence uplink.
[键盘敲击声]
[keyboard clacking]
[任]接通上行链路。
[Ren] Engaging uplink.
[自动语音]飞行员接通。
[automated voice] Pilot engaged.
[呼呼声]
[whirring]
[脉冲]
[pulsing]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[伯尼喃喃自语]
[Bernie mumbling]
那是机器人哥斯拉。
That's robot Godzilla.
哦，不。那是。。。
Oh, no. That's...
那是梅哈戈季拉。
That's Mechagodzilla.
[金属撞击声]
[metal thudding]
[金属叮当声]
[metal clanking]
[Walter]第10版。
[Walter] Release number 10.
[门砰的一声]
[gate thuds]
[咆哮声]
[snarling]
[都在尖叫]
[both screaming]
快走，快走！从那边过去！
[Bernie] Go, go! Go through there!
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[都在尖叫]
[both screaming]
麦迪逊！快跑，姑娘！
[Bernie] Madison! Run, girl!
-[骷髅虫咆哮]-[麦迪逊尖叫]
-[Skullcrawler roars] -[Madison shrieks]
[喘息声]
[gasps]
[尖叫声]
[screeching]
[轻声笑]
[chuckles softly]
[伯尼]是的！
[Bernie] Yes!
[系统断电]
[system powers down]
-[静噪]-[伯尼惊呼]
-[squelching] -[Bernie exclaims]
该死的。[叹息声]
Damn it. [sighs]
[Ren over comms]系统仅达到40%的功率。
[Ren over comms] System only reached 40% power.
[沃尔特]哦，我知道。
[Walter] Oh, I know.
一如预期。
As expected.
别担心。曾经的空心地球
Don't worry. Once the Hollow Earth
样本上传后，
sample is uploaded,
我们的电力问题会过去的。
our power troubles will be over.
[任]如果他们能找到源头。
[Ren] If they can find the source.
[沃尔特]噢，他们会找到的。我对我女儿有信心。
[Walter]  Oh, they'll find it. I have faith in my daughter.
我对我们的创造有信心。
I have faith in our creation.
人类将再次。。。
And humanity will once again...
是顶级物种。
be the apex species.
这就是为什么哥斯拉袭击了Apex设施。
This is why Godzilla attacked the Apex facility.
[嘲笑]他们想取代他。
[scoffs] They're trying to replace him.
[梅哈戈季拉的颤音]
[Mechagodzilla warbling]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
来吧，玛蒂。
[Mark] Come on, Maddie.
[信号嘟嘟声]
[signal beeping]
先生，哥斯拉刚刚
[tech on radio]  Sir, Godzilla just made
在方向上。他走得很快。
in direction. He's moving very fast.
预测显示他可能前往香港。
Projections show he's likely headed to Hong Kong.
交通工具准备好了，正等着送你去，先生。
Transport is ready and waiting to take you there, sir.
[雷劈声]
[thunder cracks]
[口中]
[mouthing]
[内森]一定是这样。
[Nathan] That has to be it.
[雷声，隆隆声]
[thunder cracks, rumbles]
[轻声咕哝]
[grunts softly]
[好奇地咆哮]
[growls inquisitively]
[紧张]
[straining]
[能量脉动]
[energy pulsating]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[呼啸声]
[roar echoes]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
我们是对的。
We were right.
他在家。
He's home.
[自动语音]所有人员必须显示
[automated voice] All personnel must display
他们的顶级员工徽章。
their Apex employee badge at all times.
跟我来。
[whispering] Follow me.
蜥蜴人建造他们所有的设施
Lizard people build all their facilities
同样的方法。我能找到出口。
the same way. I can find the exit.
[乔希喘息]
[Josh gasps]
[伯尼]出口在这边。
[Bernie] The exit's this way.
伙计们。麦迪逊！
Guys. Madison!
哦，天哪。
Oh, my God.
婊子，什么？
[Bernie] Bitch, what?
[乔希]是个泰坦头骨。
[Josh] It's a Titan skull.
[伯尼]不，不，不。那不仅仅是泰坦。
[Bernie] No, no, no. That's not just any Titan.
那是零号怪物。
That's Monster Zero.
吉多拉。
[gasps] Ghidorah.
[伯尼]他们把它的DNA连接起来了。
[Bernie] They hardwired its DNA.
自生神经通路
Self-generating neural pathways
有直觉学习能力。
capable of intuitive learning.
好吧，我很聪明，但我只上高中。
[Josh] Okay, I'm smart, but I only go to high school.
-它是一台活的超级计算机。-[乔希]嘘。
-It's a living supercomputer. -[Josh] Shh.
[难以置信地喘息]
[gasps in disbelief]
[伯尼]它有三个头。
[Bernie] It had three heads.
它的脖子很长，
Its necks were so long,
他们通过心灵感应进行交流。
they communicated telepathically.
这里有一个
And there's one here
还有一个在里面。
and another one inside of that thing.
是的，可能是灵能接口。
Yeah, it could be a psionic interface.
哦，天哪。
[exclaims] Oh, my God.
小心点。
[whispers] Careful.
[麦迪逊]是飞行员。
[Madison] It's a pilot.
[伯尼]是的。他在恍惚中。
[Bernie] Yeah. He's in a trance.
那是一个灵能上行链路。
That's a psionic uplink.
它遵循他的意愿。
It follows his will.
哦，Apex，你做了什么？
Oh, Apex, what have you done?
[人们吵吵嚷嚷]
[people clamoring and screaming]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
-[汽车警报声]-[喇叭声]
-[car alarms blaring] -[horn blaring]
[跺脚]
[stomping]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
[咆哮声]
[growling]
这是我们害怕的一天。我已经下了命令，医生。
This is the day we feared. I've given the order, Doctor.
-[人们尖叫]-城市正在疏散。
-[people screaming] -The city is being evacuated.
[尖叫声继续]
[screaming continues]
我不明白。他带我们来的。它在哪里？
[Maia] I don't understand. He led us here. Where is it?
[能量脉动]
[energy pulsates]
[咕哝声]
[grunts]
他在干什么？
[Maia] What is he doing?
【能量澎湃】
[energy surging]
是斧头。
[Ilene] It's the axe.
它从核心吸收辐射
It's drawing radiation from the core
好像在充电。
like it's charging.
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[能量充电]
[energy charging up]
[沃尔特]哇！哥斯拉在回应！他们找到了！
[Walter] Whoa! Godzilla's responding! They found it!
[汽笛声]
[siren blaring]
[马克]到底怎么了？
[Mark] What in the hell?
[机器人叽叽喳喳]
[robot chittering]
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
提取样本。
[Maia] Extracting a sample.
[伊琳]这是一种我们无法理解的力量。
[Ilene] This is a power beyond our understanding.
你不能只是钻进去。
You can't just drill into it.
实际上，我们可以。
[Maia] Actually, we can.
我父亲得到了他想要的。
My father gets what he wants.
那是Apex的财产了。
That's Apex property now.
什么？
[Ilene] What?
[系统哔哔声]
[system beeping]
能量信号传入。
Energy signature incoming.
我们很快就能重现它。
We should be able to recreate it soon.
这就是千禧年的发现。
That is the discovery of the millennium.
-你不能把它撕成碎片。-别动。
-You can't strip it for parts. -Hold it.
[枪声]
[guns cocking]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[隆隆声]
[rumbling]
[生物的尖叫声]
[creatures screeching]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growls]
去吧。去吧。得到了我们需要的。
Go. Go. Got what we needed.
走吧！
Let's go!
[嘟嘟声]
[beeping]
[沃尔特]是的。
[Walter] Yes.
Serizawa先生，启动引擎！
Mr. Serizawa, start your engines!
升级未经测试。
The upgrade is untested.
一旦我们上线，
Once we get online,
戈吉拉会直接来找我们的。
Gojira  will come straight for us.
他来找我们了
He's been coming for us
自从我们的造物第一次醒来。
since our creation first awoke.
-我们必须接受它。-我们不应该着急。
-We must embrace it. -We shouldn't rush this.
我们不知道这种能源
We have no idea how this energy source
会影响机甲。
will affect the Mecha.
去他妈的椅子上。
Get in the goddamn chair.
[守卫尖叫]
[Apex guard screaming]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growling]
[枪声]
[gunfire]
[尖峰守卫2尖叫]
[Apex guard 2 screaming]
-快，快，快！-快点，快点！
-[Maia] Go, go, go! -[pilot] Come on, come on!
快走！你在等什么？走吧！
Move! What are you waiting for? Let's go!
这边，长官！快点！我们得回去。。。
[pilot] This way, sir! Hurry! We gotta get back...
-[飞行员尖叫]-[伊琳惊呼]
-[pilot screams] -[Ilene exclaims]
[飞行员呼噜声，尖叫声]
[pilot grunts, screams]
[生物2尖叫声]
[creature 2 screeches]
[生物咆哮]
[creatures snarling]
[嘶嘶声和咆哮声]
[hissing and snarling]
[尖叫声]
[squawking]
[伊琳喘息]
[Ilene gasps]
[尖叫声]
[screeching]
可以。
Okay.
-[咕噜声]-[尖叫声]
-[grunts] -[screeches]
[尖叫声]
[screeching]
[砰的一声]
[thuds]
[孔咕噜声]
[Kong grunts]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
把他弄到一边去！开枪打他！
Get him out of the way! Shoot him!
-快，快，快！-[咆哮声]
-Go, go, go! -[roars]
[砰的一声]
[thuds]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
-[警报声]-[孔咆哮]
-[alarm blaring] -[Kong growls]
哦，不。
Oh, no.
不，不，不。。。
No, no, no...
哦，天哪！快点，我们走！
[Nathan] Oh, Jesus! Come on, let's go!
[砰的一声]
[thuds]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[怒吼]
[growls angrily]
[嘟嘟声]
[beeping]
-等等，女士们。-是的。
-Hold on, ladies. -Yeah.
[内森]哇。
[Nathan] Whoa.
[紧张地呼气]
[exhales nervously]
[嘟嘟声]
[beeping]
保持低调。
Stay low.
[相机点击]
[camera clicking]
[喘息声]
[gasps]
[轻轻地]是的。像病毒一样传播。
[softly] Yeah. Going viral.
什么？
What?
我们得试着阻止这一切。
We've gotta try and stop this.
[远处金属吱吱作响]
[metal creaking and thudding in distance]
嗯，嗯。我不喜欢这样，伙计们。
Mm-mm. I don't like this, guys.
如果这不是世界毁灭的原因，
If this wasn't contributing to world destruction,
这将是一个伟大的DJ摊位。
this would be a great DJ booth.
我知道这是什么。。。维护。
I know what it... Maintenance.
-麦迪逊，我们该走了。
-[Bernie mumbling] -Madison, we should go.
[伯尼]我是维修人员。你不必提醒。。。
[Bernie] I'm Maintenance. You don't have to alert the...
她不相信。麦迪逊，我们得走了。
She doesn't buy that. Uh, Madison, we need to go.
那个留着恶棍发型的女人。。。
The woman with the villain hairdo...
麦迪逊，他们有枪。
Madison, they have guns.
嘿，伙计们。呃，它是隔音的所以我不能。。。
Hey, guys. Uh, it's soundproof so I can't really...
-我想交流。。。-开门！
-I wanna communicate... -Open the door!
再说一遍？
Say again?
哦，天哪！趴下！趴下！
Oh, God! Get down! Get down!
哦，该死！[喘息声]
[Madison] Oh, shit! [gasps]
[紧张地笑]
[chuckles nervously]
[汽车警报声]
[car alarm blares]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growling]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[growls]
[咆哮声]
[两声怒吼]
[both roaring]
[人们尖叫]
[people screaming]
-[哥斯拉尖叫]-[孔呻吟]
-[Godzilla screeches] -[Kong groans]
[能量充电]
[energy charging up]
[孔咕噜声]
[Kong grunts]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[能量充电]
[energy charging up]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growling]
[警报声]
[sirens wailing]
[尖叫声]
[yelping]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[growls]
我们就要打破面纱了！坚持住！
We're about to breach the veil! Hold on!
[孔啸]
[Kong roaring]
[都在尖叫]
[both screaming]
-[咕噜咕噜声]-[惊呼声]
-[grunting heavily] -[exclaims]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[爆炸]
[explosion]
[咕噜声]
[grunting]
看来第二轮是去香港。
Looks like round two goes to Kong.
[伊琳喘着粗气]
[Ilene breathing heavily]
嘿！
Hey!
别这样，伙计们。真正地？又是绿色和平组织？
Oh, come on, guys. Really? Greenpeace again?
[笑]青豆。。。
[laughs] Greenpea...
事实上，先生，你不会知道的，
Actually, sir, not like you would know this,
但我是二级助理工程师。。。
but I'm Level Two Assistant Engineering...
临时二级助理工程师，
Well, Provisional Level Two Assistant Engineering,
你不会知道的。
not like you would know that.
我的评价非常鼓舞人心。。。
My evaluations were incredibly encourag...
我只是说绿色和平的愿望，这就是我要说的。
I'm just saying Greenpeace wishes, is all I'm saying.
我在哪里认识你？
Where do I know you from?
哦，天哪。
Oh, my goodness.
罗素局长的女儿，是吗？
Director Russell's daughter, yes?
这一切都是你造成的。
You caused all of this.
如果你说的“这一切”是指我，我一个人，
If by "all of this," you mean I, and I alone,
给人类一个对抗泰坦的机会，
have given humanity a chance against the Titans,
那么，是的，我将拥有这个头衔。
then, yes, I will own that title.
哥斯拉给我们留下了和平。
Godzilla had left us in peace.
你把他挑起了战争。
You provoked him into war.
只有一个阿尔法，拉塞尔小姐。
There can only be one alpha, Miss Russell.
似乎是天意。[咯咯笑]
It seems to have been providence. [chuckles]
[咆哮声]
[growling]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong groans]
[两声咆哮]
[both growling]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong groans]
[Kong groaning]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[孔呻吟]
[Kong groaning]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[呜咽声]
[whimpers]
[微弱地咆哮]
[growls weakly]
[沉思的音乐]
[pensive music playing]
是时候发射了。
[Walter over comms] It's time to launch.
开始试点整合。
Begin pilot integration.
现在。。。
And now...
我的机甲。
my Mecha.
不仅哥斯拉是平等的。。。
It's not only Godzilla's equal...
但是他的上司。
but his superior.
[Mechagodzilla通电]
[Mechagodzilla powering up]
我手上的顶点泰坦。
The Apex Titan of my own hand.
[笑]
[laughs]
是时候向全世界展示你的能力了。
[over comms]  It's time to show the world what you can do.
[自动语音]飞行员接通。
[automated voice] Pilot engaged.
警报：失败。系统不稳定。
Alert: Failure. System unstable.
[失真]警报：失败。系统不稳定。
[distorted]  Alert: Failure. System unstable.
这就是我们作为一个物种如何获胜。
This is how we, as a species, win.
你看，10年前，
You see, 10 years ago,
当Gojira第一次向世界展示的时候，
when  Gojira  was first revealed to the world,
我做了个梦。
I had a dream.
在那个梦里，我看到了一件事。
And in that dream, I saw one thing.
而那美丽，神奇的事情是。。。
And that beautiful, amazing thing was...
哦，该死。
Oh, shit.
不！
No!
[电的噼啪声]
[electricity crackling]
[咕噜声]
[grunting]
[全部咳嗽]
[all coughing]
这不公平。[咳嗽声]
It's unfair. [coughs]
我真的很想听剩下的演讲。
I really wanted to hear the rest of that speech.
[砰的一声]
[loud thudding]
[梅哈戈季拉咆哮]
[Mechagodzilla roars]
[汽车警报声]
[car alarms blaring]
看在上帝的份上那是什么？
What in God's name is that?
[颤音]
[warbling]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[人们吵吵嚷嚷]
[people clamoring and screaming]
[金属叮当声]
[metal clanking]
[呻吟声]
[groaning]
它现在在自己思考。
It's thinking for itself now.
我们必须警告君主。
We have to warn Monarch.
或者自己去阻止。
Or try to stop it ourselves.
那东西仍然和他们的卫星有关。
That thing's still linked to their satellite.
等等，乔希。
[Bernie] Wait, Josh.
[乔希]如果我能找出密码，
[Josh] If I can figure out the password,
也许我们可以把它关掉。
maybe we can shut it down.
好吧。
All right.
[内森咕哝声]
[Nathan grunts]
[伊琳喘息]
[Ilene gasps]
那到底是什么？
What the hell is that?
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[寂静降临]
[silence descends]
[微弱的心跳]
[muffled heartbeat]
什么？
What?
[手语]
[in sign language]
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
她能感觉到他的心跳。
She can feel his heartbeat.
他要死了。
He's dying.
[孔轻轻呻吟]
[Kong groaning softly]
我们没办法让他的心脏恢复正常。
There's nothing we can do to restart his heart.
我们需要足够大的费用。。。
We'd need a charge big enough to...
在拉斯维加斯开一个星期的灯。
Light up Las Vegas for a week.
[咆哮声]
[roars]
-[伯尼]这是密码吗？-[系统嗡嗡声]
-[Bernie] Is that a password? -[system buzzing]
这是密码吗？
[shouts] Is that a password?
我不知道！我不习惯这样。
I don't know! I'm not used to this.
我习惯在网上盗版电影。
I'm used to pirating movies online.
-好的，那就去设置。-[线路铃声]
-Okay, then go to Settings. -[line ringing]
-我是马克。-爸爸？
-[on phone]  This is Mark. -Dad?
麦迪逊，你在哪？
Madison, where are you?
爸爸，你能听到。。。
Dad, can you hear...
你能听见我说话吗？我在香港。
Can you hear me? I'm in Hong Kong.
-疯了？-爸爸！
-Mad? -Dad!
疯了？麦迪逊！
Mad? Madison!
[警报声]
[alarm blaring]
-[引擎启动]-哈哈！
-[engine powers up] -A-ha!
[咯咯笑]
[chuckles]
好吧，你们两个最好保持距离。
Okay, you two better get some distance.
嘿。
Hey.
你是一个非常勇敢的小女孩。
You are a very brave little girl.
[手语]
[in sign language]
我不知道。
I don't know.
也许我们都是。
Maybe we both are.
-[咆哮]-[能量充电]
-[roars] -[energy charging up]
[颤音]
[warbling]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
可以。
Okay.
祝你好运，大个子。
Good luck, big fella.
[系统警报嘟嘟声]
[system alarm beeping]
[嘟嘟声增强]
[beeping intensifies]
-[爆炸]-[孔喘息]
-[explosion] -[Kong gasps]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[喘息声]
[panting]
[手语]
[in sign language]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[growls]
[呻吟声]
[groans]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
-[骨头裂开]-[咆哮]
-[bones cracking] -[growls]
我以为你说你是黑客！
I thought you said you were a hacker!
我说我在夏令营上了HTML课程。
I said I took an HTML course at summer camp.
-HTML？-是的，在夏令营。
-HTML? -Yes, at summer camp.
是90年代的营地吗？来吧。使用QWERTY。
Was it a '90s camp? Come on. Use QWERTY.
[自动语音]错误。安全锁。
[automated voice] Error. Security lock.
-不，妈的！
-[alarm blaring] -[Josh] No. Shit!
倒霉。
Shit.
[喘着粗气]
[breathing heavily]
【哥斯拉呜咽】
[Godzilla whimpering]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
-[呼呼声]-[咆哮声]
-[whirring] -[roars]
乔希！你得做点什么。
[Madison] Josh! You have to do something.
我们想干掉那些混蛋，
We tried to take down those Apex bastards,
但我想这就是我们要做的，
but I think this is as far as we go,
所以底部向上。
so bottom's up.
我本想和大人一起死，但没关系。
I was hoping to die with adults, but okay.
[伯尼]如果你以前从没喝过酒，
[Bernie] If you've never had a drink before,
喝酒。喝酒！
Drink. Drink!
-[伯尼]嘿！你是干什么的。。。-[静态]
-[Bernie] Hey! What are you... -[static]
这就是你的解决方案？
That's your solution?
我要和你一起死，清醒点！
I gotta die here with you, and sober!
[爆炸]
[explosion]
[呼啸声]
[whirring stops]
[电的噼啪声]
[electricity crackling]
[孔咆哮]
[Kong growls]
【能量澎湃】
[energy surging]
[咕哝声]
[grunts]
[孔啸]
[Kong roars]
-[伯尼]耶！-[乔希]是的！对！
-[Bernie] Yeah! -[Josh] Yes! Yes!
[金属叮当声]
[metal clangs]
[咆哮声]
[growls]
[roars]
[电的噼啪声]
[electricity crackling]
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[呻吟声]
[groaning]
嘿，内森？
[echoes] Hey, Nathan?
[轻器乐演奏]
[soft instrumental music plays]
-内森？-[轻轻地喘息]
-Nathan? -[gasps softly]
内森，你没事吧？
Nathan, are you okay?
[直升机盘旋]
[helicopters hovering]
[人群喋喋不休]
[crowd chattering]
[警报声]
[sirens wailing]
爸爸？
Dad?
爸爸！
Dad!
[马克喘息]
[Mark gasps]
[哭]
[crying]
你好。呃，那是，呃。。。麦迪逊的主意。
Hi. Um, it was, um... Madison's idea.
闭嘴，乔希。
Shut up, Josh.
爸爸。这就是那个救了我们的人。
Dad. This is the man who saved our lives.
伯尼，见见爸爸。
Bernie, meet Dad.
爸爸。呃，伯尼。
Dad. Uh, Bernie.
嗯，很高兴见到你。
Um, it's an absolute pleasure to meet you.
[犹豫]我想知道我是否可以邀请你
[hesitates] I was wondering if I could invite you
谈论罗斯韦尔的Monarch设施是因为。。。
to talk about the Monarch facility in Roswell because...
[伯尼含糊不清地继续说]
[Bernie continues indistinctly]
太神奇了。事情发生了。。。
It's amazing. It happened...
-[哥斯拉咆哮]-[伯尼尖叫]
-[Godzilla roars] -[Bernie screams]
[孔咕噜]
[Kong grunting]
贾？贾！
Jia? Jia!
[咆哮声]
[roars]
[哥斯拉咆哮]
[Godzilla roars]
[“我呼吸的空气”演奏]
["The Air That I Breathe" playing]
[含糊不清的喋喋不休]
[indistinct chatter]
小心点，伙计们！他早上要过来散步。
Heads up, guys! He's coming around for his morning walk.
[男人喊叫]
[men shouting]
[手语]
[in sign language]
有时
♪  Sometimes ♪
[咕噜声]
[grunting]
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
[呼啸声]
[roar echoes]
“爱你”
♪ And to love you ♪
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
是的，爱你
♪ Yes, to love you ♪
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
有时
♪ Sometimes ♪
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
“爱你”
♪ And to love you ♪
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
“爱你”
♪ And to love you ♪
我只需要呼吸空气
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe ♪
是的，爱你
♪ Yes, to love you ♪
[播放戏剧音乐]
[dramatic music playing]